parentree.in 2017-06-02

# Parentree - Privacy POlicy

**Privacy-policy**

Last updated: May 4 2014 12:00PM IST

Parentree ("Parentree") operates websites across multiple domain and subdomain names (the "Sites") including this one. Parentree provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive from users who access our Sites ("Visitors") and users who register at our Sites and then access them ("Members"). This Privacy Policy is to give you an idea of what information is collected and how it is used. By accessing and/or registering at the Sites you agree and consent to the collection, use and disclosure of information as detailed in this Privacy Policy. 

**Information Collection**

The following list of information is collected based on user submissions:

When Members register at the Sites, registration information including but not limited to name, email, nickname, gender, city, country, and access to other 3rd party user authorizing websites  
Members can voluntarily enhance their personal profiles on the website through various ways including but not limited to uploading a photo, expressing their interests, self descriptions, information about their children  
Members may also provide personal information when they use various tools like due date calculator, ovulation calculator, child growth charts  
Content including text, graphic, materials, messages contributed by the Members during their use of the site through blogs, groups, reviews and ratings.

The following information is collected automatically:

Information sent by your browser when you visit the Sites including but not limited to Internet Protocol address, browser type, operating system type, the content you access  
Like many websites, Parentree's Sites also use "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard disk. Parentree's Sites use "persistent cookies" to save your login information to future access to the Sites and "session ID cookies" to enable certain features of the sites and to make the experience customized for you. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of our services.  
We also use web traffic analysis tools from Google (Google Analytics) which may log similar automatic information as above.  
We also use web traffic analysis tools from Google (Google Analytics) which may log additional information about you using their own "cookies", including age, gender, interests, sites you visit and more. Please read their respective privacy policies to understand the options available to you.  
We also use third party tools like Addthis, Facebook Connect, and Google to provide various functionalities, and they may log similar automatic information as above.

 **Information usage**

Personal Information is used for the following purposes:

To provide and improve our Sites, features, content and services  
To administer your use of our Sites  
To personalize your experience  
To assist you and other Members and Visitors share content with each other and learn from each other  
To send you updates about the Sites, content, messages and features. You can opt out of these updates by editing your account settings  
To help Members like you discover what your friends are doing on the Sites. You can choose who will be your friends on the Sites.  
We use information we obtain by automatic technical means (such as the automatic recording performed by our servers or through the use of cookies) for the above purposes and in order to monitor and analyze use of the Sites and our services and for the Sites' technical administration, to increase our Sites' functionality and user-friendliness, to better tailor it to your needs, to generate and derive useful data and information concerning the interests, characteristics and website use behaviour of our users, and to verify that Visitors to and Members of the Sites meet the criteria required to process their requests.

 **Information Sharing and Transfer**

Members

Your nickname, photo, city and country will be visible to all Visitors to the site. You can choose not to provide a photo and instead use a generic graphic.   
All content you contribute to the Sites, except in your Inbox, will be visible to all Visitors to the site and is thus in the public domain.  
When you generate content (blogs, comments, discussions, reviews, ratings) automatic updates are sent to other Members who you have specifically accepted as your friends or who have contributed to the same areas of content. These updates cannot be turned off.  
To understand this in granular detail, please access the Feedback and Features groups at http://www.parentree.in//, which are incorporated herein by reference.  
Any enhanced personal profile information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want Members to know about you. We recommend that you guard your sensitive information and we encourage Members to think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their enhanced personal profile pages and in the content they post. You can review and revise your profile information at any time.

Service Providers, Business Partners and Others

We will not sell your name, or your email address to anyone.  
We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our service, to provide the services on our behalf, to perform Sites-related services (including but not limited to maintenance services, server management, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Sites features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Sites, content and services are used. These third parties have access to your personal information only for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf.  
We may provide content from the Sites, including content contributed by you, to third parties for commercial gain. The selection of third parties will be done only after careful consideration. When this is done, we will provide only the profile information that we make available to Visitors to the Sites. Any personal information you made available as part of the content you contributed (blogs, groups, reviews etc.,) may also be transferred to these third parties as we have no way of filtering that out.  
We will use anonymous, aggregated data for normal business purposes or in dealings with other parties.

 **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement**

Parentree cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. Parentree will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Parentree or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical, inappropriate or legally actionable.

 **Business Transfers**

Parentree may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including all information and content you provide, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.

 **Changing or Deleting Your Information**

All Members may review, or update the information provided in their registration or enhanced personal profiles by accessing their account.  
Members also have the ability to delete blog entries in their blogs and replies they have made in discussions, within 72 hours (Parentree may change this period at its own discretion without notice) of posting the content.  
Members also have the ability to terminate their membership of the site. Their registration information, enhanced personal profiles, blog entries, and all friend relationships are deleted on membership termination. All other information including but not limited to comments they made in the blogs of other Members or former Members, reviews of products and service providers, any ratings they made on the Sites, discussions started or replied to, will all continue to remain on the site but will no longer be identifiable as belonging to an individual unless the Member added personally identifiable information in the body of the content.  
Where Parentree terminates a Member's registration, for violation of the Terms of Services, we will keep their email addresses or other information provided from 3rd party user authorizing websites, on record to prevent them from becoming a Member again.  
Parentree may make archives of the Sites and all the content, logs, and any other server information, in the normal course of business. Any changes made by Members to their profiles or termination of their membership will not be reflected in the archives, which are snapshots in time.

 **Security**

Parentree is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ reasonable measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. You hereby acknowledge that Parentree is not responsible for any intercepted information sent via the Internet, and you hereby release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of intercepted information in any unauthorized manner.

 **Children's Privacy**

The Sites are not directed to anyone under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 18. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personal information without their consent, he or she should contact us at support [at] parentree.in. If we become aware that a person under 18 has provided us with personal information, we will terminate their memberships.

 **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or need to contact us about privacy, please email to support [at] parentree.in 

All Rights Reserved Copyright © 2008-2017 Parentree
